<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Gripes | Danielogical]]></title>
  <link href="http://DanielBaird.github.com/blog/categories/gripes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://DanielBaird.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-27T12:28:38+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://DanielBaird.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Daniel Baird]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[daniel@danielbaird.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unskippable bits on DVDs]]></title>
    <link href="http://DanielBaird.github.com/blog/2006/05/26/unskippable-bits-on-dvds/"/>
    <updated>2006-05-26T13:58:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://DanielBaird.github.com/blog/2006/05/26/unskippable-bits-on-dvds</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>DVDs often stop me from fast-forwarding through the stuff that plays before the movie, and that sucks.</p>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DVD#DVD-Video">Apparently</a> this is an example of User Operation Prohibitions, or UOPs.  I'm forced to sit through studio branding, copyright warnings, government ads telling me that "piracy is stealing", and even the frickin' animations that introduce the menu.</p>

<p>What is the point of this?  The movie studio must have some good reasons for preventing viewers from skipping those parts.  Here's some reasons I can think of:</p>

<ul>
<li>by forcing me to watch the studio branding bit, where the camera zooms around inside some indistinguishable object, and eventually pulls back, revealing the object to be a big horse or a tree or something.. the studio is marketing itself to me.</li>
</ul>


<p>Okay, but what's actually happening here is that the DVD I just bought is showing me the logo of a particular movie studio, and <em>simultaneously pissing me off</em>.</p>

<ul>
<li>by forcing me to watch a stupid ad where some Young Person is downloading a movie off the web, and cutting in scenes of people stealing cars and handbags and whatnot, and eventually showing the Young Person cancelling the download whilst telling me that "piracy is stealing", I'm less likely to watch pirated movies.</li>
</ul>


<p>Firstly, why does the ad show someone downloading a movie?  <em>I've already got the movie, I'm watching it right now</em> (or I would be, if I could skip over this crap).  Surely it would be more useful to show someone not copying their DVD for their friends, rather than not downloading it.</p>

<p>I'm pretty sure that the people who are downloading movies already know that it's illegal.  It doesn't help that the ad is trying to draw a parallel between copying movies and stealing cars, because apart from both being illegal, they're quite obviously different things.  Copyright infringement is bad, but <a href="http://www.mp3newswire.net/stories/5002/theft.html">it's arguable</a> whether it's "stealing" at all; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theft">most definitions of theft</a> involve depriving the rightful owner of possession of the item.</p>

<p>There is one thing the ad does pretty well; if it hadn't occurred to someone that they could download movies from the web, they sure know it now.  So at least it's educational.</p>

<ul>
<li>by forcing me to look at the copyright/FBI warning for 60 seconds, I might pay more attention to the information presented there.</li>
</ul>


<p>Nnnnnnnope.  Who reads that stuff?  No-one, doesn't matter how long you leave it up on screen.</p>

<p>The only reason it is there is so if the studio want to charge someone with copyright infringement (or whatever it's called in the US now since the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DMCA">DMCA</a>.. it's probably been renamed "treason against America" or something), the defendant can't claim that they never knew it was against the law.  Okay, that's a good reason to have it there, but <em>why stop me from skipping it</em>?</p>

<ul>
<li>The little intro animation as the menu scrolls into view are, um, cute.</li>
</ul>


<p>This is the best I can come up with, because there's <em>no reason on earth</em> to have the menu intro unskippable.  My daughter watches Fairytopia five times a day!  Do I have to watch Fairy Barbie flutter around the screen for thirty seconds every Fairy Freakin' time?</p>

<p>Stuart Little is even worse; even when the menu is completely showing and appears ready to use, you still have to wait for Stuart to finish saying something like "Hi there.  Hope you enjoy the movie" before you can hit the Play Movie button.</p>

<p>While "researching" this article, I discovered that (according to Wikipedia) grey market DVD players often ignore UOPs, and let you skip whatever you like.  So I'm off shopping today for a grey market DVD player.  See what you've done, movie studio DVD divisons?  You've forced me go and buy a player that ignores region coding and all that other stuff, just to be able to skip the pre-movie crap.</p>

<p>Not being able to skip pre-movie stuff sucks.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
